CHRISTOPHER BURNETTE

Full Stack Developer - React, Node.js, Vue, AWS

OVERVIEW

Full stack developer with 8 years of experience developing software products using JavaScript and its frameworks such as React, Next.js, Vue.js and Node.js.

I provide effective solutions by using best practices and pragmatic methods bundled with my mastery of business and technical skills gained from many years of professional experience. I help organizations and people realize their goals of growth and success.

I have gained much business-specific knowledge by working within the following business domains: banking, education, entertainment, environment, finance, insurance, loans, management, marketing, retail, and sales.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Tailwind CSS, Node.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Material UI, Styled Components, Amazon Web Service, Cron Jobs, Responsive Design, GraphQL, MVC, Git, CI/CD, Docker, Kubernetes, GCP, Bigquery

EXPERIENCE

SELF-EMPLOYED, FREELANCE - FULL STACK DEVELOPER

JUL 2020 - NOV 2022

- With Covid-19, I finally started my own freelance enterprise, worked on my own terms and supplemented my income.
- Remote Contract work for various clients, from small, unique apps to complete corporate web products. Mostly React.js, Next.js, Gatsby, Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, GCP, AWS, and various other tools.
- Worked on Architecture and design of modernization projects for multiple legacy web applications.
- Collaborated with an agile team to maintain and add new features for existing microservices

BROUGHE CONSTRUCTION, FULL TIME — SENIOR REACT & NODE.JS FULL STACK DEVELOPER

SEP 2018 - JUN 2020

- Worked as a web developer to build semantically structured full-stack web applications using React, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, Express, AWS and user authentication
- Designed and built simple, tasteful Commercial/Residential/eCommerce websites, brand portfolios, and mockup sites for clients.

- Built semantically structured full-stack web applications for mobile and desktop devices
- Gained much business-specific knowledge by working within the following business domains: Commercial, Residential, banking, retail, marketing, and sales.

BROADCASTER, INC., FULL TIME - NODE.JS BACKEND DEVELOPER

AUG 2017 - JUL 2018

- Worked on a Client SaaS product to which I contributed the following: token based user authentication, a subscription payment system using Stripe, integrated Facebook and Google's APIs, and the entire web application UI using React. I also integrated the following AWS services: S3, SES, and Elastic Transcoder.
- This included coordinating various development groups, deciding part of the software stack for a large ecosystem, and designing both backend and frontend architecture.

PENNYMAC, FULL TIME - REACT & NODE.JS FULL STACK DEVELOPER

OCT 2015 - JUL 2017

- Worked as a full stack developer on pricing and other micro services involved in end to end development of Microservices
- Wrote an algorithm to auto assign loans to agents based on interchangeable criteria.
- Deployed changes after each agile sprint cycle to production systems.
- Worked on the source code being compatible with Swagger/OpenAPI spec for easy documentation.
- Technologies: React and AWS serverless, Node Lambda, API Gateway, WebSockets, S3, DynamoDB, EventBridge, CloudFormation, SAM CLI

EDUCATION

University of North Texas — BS, Computer Science

FEB 2012 - MAR 2015